# **Edward Ragin**

## Desktop Support Engineer - Department of Interior, National Park Service

Sicklerville, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Edward-Ragin/9dbd3471d4e4e5ab

Computer support technician with over ten years' experience providing technical assistance to business professionals. Demonstrated ability to integrate computer skills, customer support experience, and related education to exceed technical, business, and customer requirements. Skilled at troubleshooting and fixing problems while minimizing customer stress levels. Professionally certified by CompTIA.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Desktop Support Engineer**

NuAxis Innovations, Vienna, VA - Contractor, Contracted to Department of Interior, National Park Service

- Philadelphia, PA - October 2012 to Present

Takes incoming requests for support via phone, email, or walk-ins, gather information from end user and create trouble tickets

- > Installs and configures corporate image on desktops and laptops
- > Encrypts all laptops per corporate compliance; and maintains encryption software
- > Configures and installs offline and network printers
- > Configures iPhones and Android devices per corporate compliance
- > Conducts independent research to learn support tips in desktop utilization and software improvement suggestions, and present findings to supervisor.
- > Prepares Polycom audio/video conference system for end-users
- > Manages Active Directory in a corporate environment

#### Senior Desktop Support Specialist

URL Pharma - Philadelphia, PA - May 2012 to October 2012

Philadelphia, PA

Senior Desktop Support Specialist

- > Achieved highest client support ratings in the department and exceeded standards for trouble ticket turnaround times
- > Provided internal customer support for various divisions of the company
- > Installed, configured and troubleshoot computer hardware, operating systems, network configurations and software
- > Maintain Symantec Antivirus architecture; perform updates and patches as required
- > Author user manuals and desktop standard
- > Assist with the installation, configuration and ongoing usability of desktop computers, peripheral equipment and software
- > Trains and orients client staff on use of hardware and software
- > Supports 400 end users in many aspects of the hardware and software environment
- > Install hardware, applications, maintain LAN / WAN / Wireless networks, support remote access users, develop documentation, the IT team
- > Prepare and present report to management on organization's security and virus protection audit
- > Builds and maintains computer Ghost images for the company

# **Desktop Support Specialist**

URL Pharma - Philadelphia, PA - September 2006 to May 2012

Installed and configured over 275 new desktop systems

- > Participated in the training of users on use of network hardware and software.
- > Maintained the LAN network operations, including limited hardware and software installation and set-up, documentation, administration, technical maintenance and user support
- > Troubleshoot network problems and coordinate preventative maintenance of equipment
- > Maintained and tracked hardware and software inventory and documents all problems
- > Responsible for ensuring compliance with all software licensing requirements
- > Liaised with Regional Technology Engineers, external Help Desk, and vendor specialists in seeking solutions to equipment failures

# **Internal/External Technical Support**

UPS - Lawnside, NJ - July 1998 to February 2006

Provided support for UPS internal users in a LAN environment

- > Provided desk side support for external clients
- > Installed computers, monitors and label printers
- > Installed MS OS patches and service packs; configures and supported commercial Off-The-Shelf applications

### **EDUCATION**

#### A.A.S

Computer Learning Center - Plymouth Meeting, PA March 1997 to April 1998

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Core Competencies

- ➤ Desktop
- ➤ Laptop
- > Helpdesk Operations
- > Networking
- > Symantec Ghost
- > Polycom Audio/Video Conference System
- ➤ Juniper & Cisco VPN
- > Microsoft Lync
- ➤ Microsoft Windows
- > Microsoft Office
- > Microsoft SCCM
- ➤ Microsoft SharePoint
- > Microsoft Active Directory
- ➤ System Maintenance
- ➤ Mac OS X
- > Symantec Endpoint Protection

Administration

➤ McAfee Endpoint Encryption

➤ Maas360 for iOS and Android